Devesh Srivastava

LEAD FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Lead full stack developer with total 14 years of experience in frontend, backend with single responsive page including React, Ruby on Rails, Angular, Node.js, .Net,C#, MVC, CI/CD deployment Azure/AWS cloud, Docker/ Kubernetesand lead team across a range of agile centric and waterfall delivery model. Worked on Technical Lead role at onshore client site for more than 5 Years in UK.



devesh.kr.sri@gmail.com

(+91) 9999305585

Delhi, India

deveshprofile.herokuapp.com/

linkedin.com/in/devesh-srivastava-94268516 in

devesh.kr.srivastava@gmail.com 🔕

github.com/deveshprojectwork 🧻

SKILLS

ReactJS, Redux, Hook EmberJS, Webpack, Babel Material UI, Forma 36, Prime React OAuth, JWT HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap Asp.net, C#, MVC JavaScript, Typescript BACK END - Node.js, .Net Core API GraphQL, REST APIs Microservices Git, GitHub,TFS, Jira TESTING -: Jest, Karma, Jasmine, RSpec DATABASE- MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL Server DEPLOYMENT: Jenkin pipeline with Kubernetes, Docker, Ansible Heroku, AWS, Azure-devops Agile, Kanban

WORK EXPERIENCE

LEAD FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Digital Squad, NBS UK

03/2018 - Present Accenture UK

Working as a Full Stack Developer in Leading UK Bank in mortgages to facilitate its digital transformation form on-premise to cloud. Achievements/Tasks

- Solution Design of overall front end and back end application for digital mortgage sales using React.JS, Redux, Hooks, MongoDB, GraphQL & REST API, CSS3, HTML5, Typescript, JavaScript, Node.js & CI/CD.
- Setup CI/CD pipeline with Jenkins and Azure Devops to deploy applications to multiple production server in Azure/AWS cloud with Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible.
- Delivering Solution Concepts, estimation for upgrading and supporting legacy application to .net application.
- Led end-to-end technical consulting engagements for enterprise clients building internal software development with performed planning, estimation, coding, bug fixing, code reviews.
- Implemented Bootstrap, Material UI, Prime react and Server side rendering, oAuth, JWT Token in the project.

LEAD FULL STACK DEVELOPER

NATIONWIDE BUILDING SOCIETY, UK

04/2015 - 03/2018 Accenture UK

Designed and developed responsive single page components for a variety of applications in an agile development setting in MDC.

Achievements/Tasks

- Create custom components in React JS, Redux (internal UI library) that can be used company wide so that we have common UI
 across applications.
- Support the development of the Angular application with Core API with Sql Server.
- Design and implementation of the 99.99% up-time REST API for the business-critical banking application.
- Collaborates with client-side business leaders to scope IT process reviews, allocate resources, and oversees service transitions
 e.g. analyzing service data, interviewing users, and recommending solutions that support clients' strategic objectives.



WORK EXPERIENCE

SR. SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CBIA Project- Accenture UK/India

09/2011 - 03/2015 Worked with a large UK financial banking projects for Digital applications.

Achievements/Tasks

- Architected and designed enterprise applications for project using Angular, AWS Lambda, & SQL server.
- Design and implementation of the 99.99% up-time REST API for the business-critical online service.
- Build technical architecture for reporting applications.
- Supported MVC, .net, C# project to build front end application.
- Consulted in a redesign of the company's website, resulting in a 25% increase in traffic.

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

ITALFONDIARIO Project

09/2009 - 09/2011 Accenture India

Worked with large financial banking applications for the development and support of applications.

- Lead Development team for banking applications. Developed web applications using C#, ASP.NET MVC, JavaScript, and CSS.
- Implement the module based on the change request, along with the build, code review, unit testing & deployment of the application.
- Ensure proper documentation and reports in all stages of the application development life cycle.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF COMPUTER APPLICATION

IGNOU, DELHI

05/2005

ACHIEVEMENTS

CertifiedScrumMaster®(CSM) form Scrum Alliance

Microsoft Azure Cloud Certified (Developer and Administrator)

Inc.

NATIONWIDE BUILDING SOCIETY

PRIDE AWARD AT ACCENTURE FOR OUTSTANDING CONTRIBUTION **TO THE PROJECT IN 2018 & 2019**

ORGANIZATIONS

ACCENTURE PRIVATE LIMITED (08/2009 - Present)

Team Lead

PATNI COMPUTER SYSTEM (01/2008 - 08/2009)

SR.Software Engineer

FCF Software Solution LTD (06/2006 - 07/2007)

Software Engineer

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend React.JS, Ruby on Rails, Angular, Typescript, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap

Backend Node.js, .Net Framework, RESTApi, TDD, and .Net Core API

Cloud platforms AWS, Heroku, Azure (Web Service, Function, Storage, Database)

Testing Mocha, Jest, Selenium, JUnit, NUnit

Database MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MYSQL, SQL Server

Collaboration Confluence, JIRA, Agile

Dev-Ops/CI-CD Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Azure DevOps, Ansible

Domain Banking, Finance, Manufacturing Accenture India/UK